- [Interviewer] If you\nwere alone in a room
with a gay pastor, what would you ask?
- Do you view yourself\nas an openly gay pastor
- What are your thoughts\non conversion therapy?
- Does it really say in the\nBible that being gay is a sin?
- So the first thing is we\nhave to look at is that...
- Hi, I'm Hadidas, and I have\nsome questions for you today.
- Awesome. Nice to meet you, Hadidas.
- My first question is,\nwhat is your religion?
- I am a progressive Pentecostal
- What inspired you to become a Pastor?
- It's a funny story. I really\ndidn't desire to be a pastor.
I wanted to be a police officer.
And so I always joke when I'm preaching
There was a church looking\nfor a youth leader
developed a passion and a love for it.
- Is being gay ever an issue for you?
Like, does that affect you\nbeing a pastor in any way?
I get uninvited to stuff\nand I'm the black sheep
You know, something happened\nthat was really funny.
One of my friends invited me to come
Some of the members from that congregation
wanted to hear me again,\nso they came to my church.
I wanted to thank God for\nmy boyfriend being there
and I saw every person that\ncame from that congregation
they got up and exited, stage right.
that I'm going to hell and\nI'm teaching false doctrine.
In the beginning of my\nministry, that hurt me.
On the flip side, when a\nyoung person comes to you
and they're thinking\nabout committing suicide
then who's gonna hold\nthem up and tell them
You know what, you don\'t have to give up
and you don\'t have to allow\npeople to dictate your path.
You have the power to\ndictate your own path.
- I definitely resonate with that a lot.
- Have you ever had to hide yourself
- I don't think that I hid my sexuality
or hid who I am but I did\nuse a lot of discretion
so that I wouldn't offend people.
It took me until 26 to actually,\nauthentically, be myself.
I went through this journey of\ndating girls and dating guys.
I would go out with my girlfriend
because I wanted everybody\nin the church to love me
and to like me and then I would go home
and cuddle with my boyfriend after.
It wasn\'t until like I\nhad an "ahoo" moment
I just said basically to hell with people
and I understand that God created me
and he built me to be\nthe person that I am.
And nobody can be Curt but Curt.
(Curt clapping)\n- Yay! (giggling)
And it definitely took me a bit longer
than I would've liked\nto have figured it out.
- How did the acceptance in the church
of queer people affect you\nand your own mental state?
- I don't think my\nsexuality was exposed yet.
But I will tell you\nthat I use hand gestures
and the bishop called me into\nhis office and he was like
All those, those hand\ngestures and stuff like that
that you\'re doing, men, don\'t do that.
It triggered me to where\nif I move my hands
I'll catch myself, put my hands together
and say, no, don't move your hands.
- I remember I had a similar experience
not so much hand movements,\nbut the way I walked.
Like, I remember it was\nlike three of the older guys
were like, "You know,\nyou walk like a girl.
Why is your butt out like that?
And I didn't think I was\nwalking like so flamboyantly
but that moment stuck with me up until now
- I think that in the\nworld that we live in today
that we can actually be more gender fluid.
- And if you like it, you\nlike it, make it work.
So that's how the world needs to be.
- How does your family\nhandle your sexuality
- My family is very understanding.
In all actuality, my parents\nare members of my church.
I don't really have a coming out story
because I really never came out
I just became more authentically myself.
But I will say I had\nan initial conversation
My mom said that she already knew.
he would use terms like\n'them' and 'those people.'
Now he understands that\nat the end of the day
- Have you ever taken\nand 'Am I gay?' quiz?
- Okay.\n- That's why I asked.
- Do you view yourself\nas an openly gay pastor
that I'm passionate about people
and that God has called me and\ngiving me a unique identifier
to be able to love and to appreciate
and to speak life into people.
- Does it really say in the\nBible that being gay is a sin?
- Biblical text doesn't\nintroduce the word homosexuality
And so then you have to go back
and you have to look at\nthe original manuscript
which frames it from a\ndifferent perspective.
So it talks about giving\nthe natural affection
of a man to a woman or a woman to a man.
Well, what is your natural affection?
Is your natural affection to a man
or is your natural affection to a woman?
We are divinely everything\nthat God wants us to be.
I've never heard that part of it before.
- What are your thoughts\non conversion therapy?
- Oh, I think there's the stupidest thing
and I hope that whoever does that
I hope that they find a guiding light.
People can't be converted from\nwho they authentically are.
There's something that was called Exodus.
and they would stay there and pray
and think that that would\nchange their situation.
they were sneaking in each\nother's rooms late at night
so it didn't work. (chuckling)
- Do you believe that you will go to hell?
- Oh, hecky by jecky, no.\nI'm not going to hell.
I think that God is very heart intended
I don't think in him, there's\nneither male nor female.
- I definitely think that\nGod looks at your soul
and not at who you choose to love.
- How does it make you feel\nwhen more conservative pastors
spread hate about the LGBTQ community
and even like spread like threats?
- It hurts my feelings\nthat people operate in hate
especially when we serve a God that loves.
John 3:16 says, "For\nGod so loved the world.
When people teach hate instead of love
it makes me one, question their ability
to really hear from God\nor to speak for God.
- Was there ever a time that\nyou resented the church?
- Yes, I had a situation where I was fired
and I resented the church\nfor a very long time.
My therapist was able\nto help me understand
how to feel better about myself.
- So how does one take religion
and come to terms with themselves?
Like, this is that love\nyou're talking about.
is that people want to be religious.
God's desire is to be relational with us.
If we go back to Genesis\nand we look in the garden
with Adam and Eve, God was\nbuilding relationship with them
he wasn't building religion with them.
- Do you ever get any\njudgment from queer people
- So many gay people have been hurt
You know, it does take people a minute
to realize that religion\nis not what we do
- What advice would you\ngive to a gay person
who is fearful of going to church?
- You can Google and find churches
that are inclusive and accepting
and then after you do that\nyou have to find a church
that meets your specific needs.
I think one of the downfalls\nwith going to just any church
is that some churches are tolerant
is a church where you won't see anybody
that looks like you in the leadership.
I started my church 12 years ago
because I wanted to\nmake sure that there was
a place where people could\nfeel comfortable and safe.
My church is not just a gay church.
So you have straight\npeople, you have gay people
you have upside down people, you know
we're like Dr. Seuss, you know
it's a table full of everybody.
- So would you say your church is like
or is it more on like quiet side?
Jump, scream, holler, enjoy\nyourself while you're there.
Renewed, which is the name of my church.
You can experience renewal\nin whatever process or way
We have this time in the service\nwhere we do meet and greet
and a girl came up to me after,\nat the end of the service
and said that she hadn't been\nhugged by anyone in two years.
- Just knowing that someone like you
as an openly queer pastor is\njust out there in the world
and just like a young little gay boy
is able to look at you and be like, wow
is very special to me and I\nwant thank you personally.
So you say, I'm out here\nand I'm out here to stay.
- [Interviewer] Would you\nguys like to meet each other?
- Ah, I knew it was you.\n- It's me!
Oh, I don't even want to\nthink about it like that.